

MELHEM EL DIRANI

+961-71-523153



melhemdirani@hotmail.com



melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/



REACT DEVELOPER/ PROJECT MANAGER

Saida, Lebanon



PROFILE ME

An experienced self-taught web developer. Having owned and developed an online digital agency that provides web based services like web/mobile app development and design. Expertise in developing, testing and maintaining web applications using html, css, javascript and other frameworks and libraries like react, react native, redux and nodejs. Known for being a cheerful, caring, practical, motivational and commercially minded team-player. A lover of life and people, aiming to create a healthy work environment, gain valuable experience and help others grow their skills.

EXPERIENCE

2021 - present

Reboost Lebanon

WEB DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEADER / CEO

- Designing, building and configuring applications to meet business process and application requirements
- Directing the development team in the design, development, coding, testing and debugging of applications
- · Writing testable, scalable and efficient code and leading code reviews
- Mentoring junior team members and ensuring they adhere to determined software quality standards
- Planning and documenting technical specifications for features or system design

2020 - present

Self employed Remotely

WEB DEVELOPMENT FREELANCER

- Develop web applications using Javascript, React, Sass, Nodejs and Postgresql
- · Coordinating directly with clients
- Using content managing systems like Wordpress and Shopify to develop web application as well as building cms using React, Nodejs and Postgresql

2021 - 2021

Sicilia Mia Italy

INTERN FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER, SICILIA MIA

- Reviewing application requirements and interface designs. Developing and implementing highly-responsive user interface components using React concepts.
- Writing application interface codes using JavaScript following React.js workflows and frameworks like Redux. Troubleshooting interface software and debugging application codes.
- · Developing and implementing front-end architecture to support user interface concepts.
- Monitoring and improving front-end performance.

SKILLS

EDUCATION

2016 -2018

Rafik Hariri University Mechref, Lebanon

MASTER DEGREE IN CIVIL **ENGINEERING**

Web Development



Leadership



Problem Solving



2015 - 2019

Lebanese University Saida, Lebanon

BACHELOR DEGREE IN CIVIL **ENGINEERING**





Check out my portfolio for more projects: melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/

MAWAHIB MOBILE APP

- App store link: https://apps.apple.com/lb/app/mawahib/id1638967746
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: React native & Nodejs

WEBSITE + DASHBOARD FOR DANASH CONTRACTING

- WEBSITE: https://mdanash.com/
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Javascript, Sass, Nodejs andPostgresql

PORTFOLIO FOR NFT LAB

- WEBSITE: https://lsdlab.io/
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Javascript & CSS

LANDING PAGE FOR BLUVOWS

- WEBSITE: https://bluvows.com/greece/
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: Wordpress

SHOP FOR RAYAN DATES

- WEBSITE: https://rayandates.com/
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: Shopify

WEBSITE FOR REBOOST

- WEBSITE: https://reboost.live/
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Javascript, Sass, Nodejs and Mongodb

LANGUAGES

English

Arabic • • • • • •

French • • • • • •